<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ursa Labs</title>
    <link>https://ursalabs.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ursa Labs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2018-2020 Ursa Labs</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ursalabs.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward an Arrow-native world: the next stage of the Ursa journey</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/ursa-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/ursa-computing/</guid>
      <description>Since launching Ursa Labs in 2018, we have made extraordinary progress growing the Apache Arrow project and supporting the open source community around it. As I explained in my announcement of the initiative, our objective has been to create a robust engineering team in partnership with a wide variety of sponsoring companies with the Arrow project&#39;s success as our number one priority. Since then, we have added NVIDIA, Intel, Bloomberg, G-Research, and OneSixtyTwo Technologies (and some others we cannot name publicly) to our sponsor ranks, joining our founding sponsors RStudio and Two Sigma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chan Zuckerberg Initiative funds new Apprenticeship program to foster diversity and inclusion in Apache Arrow</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2020-czi-ursa-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2020-czi-ursa-labs/</guid>
      <description>We founded Ursa Labs in 2018 to build a team to enable Apache Arrow to be a robust and reliable next-generation computational foundation for in-memory analytics and data science. To make this possible, we partnered with RStudio, Two Sigma, and several other corporate sponsors to secure the financial support for a group of full time open source developers. In part through our efforts, Arrow is now installed more than ten million times per month by Python and R users and has quickly become one of the most important technologies for working with large tabular datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feather V2 with Compression Support in Apache Arrow 0.17.0</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2020-feather-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2020-feather-v2/</guid>
      <description>Back in October 2019, we took a look at performance and file sizes for a handful of binary file formats for storing data frames in Python and R. These included Apache Parquet, Feather, and FST.
In the intervening months, we have developed &amp;ldquo;Feather V2&amp;rdquo;, an evolved version of the Feather format with compression support and complete coverage for Arrow data types. In this post, we explain what Feather V2 is and what you might find it useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast pandas DataFrame loading from Apache Arrow</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/fast-pandas-loading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/fast-pandas-loading/</guid>
      <description>A Surprising Performance Experiment To start off this blog post, I&#39;ll present a surprising fact. The pyarrow library is able to construct a pandas.DataFrame faster than using pandas.DataFrame directly in some cases. Let&#39;s have a look.
First, I make a dict of 100 NumPy arrays of float64 type, a little under 800 megabytes of data:
import pandas as pd import pyarrow as pa import numpy as np num_rows = 1_000_000 num_columns = 100 arr = np.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ursa Labs: 2019 Highlights and 2020 Outlook</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2020-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2020-outlook/</guid>
      <description>2020 in Apache Arrow development has gotten off to a running start with a 0.16.0 major release around the corner and a 1.0.0 release (including protocol stability guarantees) coming with luck in the first half of the year.
In this blog post, we would like to summarize Ursa Labs development highlights from 2019 and highlight our major focus areas and priorities for 2020. Apache Arrow libraries provide an efficient and high performance development platform that addresses, broadly speaking:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing New Ursa Labs Sponsors</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2020-new-sponsors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2020-new-sponsors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that Ursa Labs has several new sponsors supporting
our work on Apache Arrow over the coming year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;G-Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OneSixtyTwo Technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ursa Labs Team Report August to December 2019</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-12-19-eoy-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-12-19-eoy-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With a busy fall full of development and some travel I wasn&#39;t able to keep up
with monthly or bi-monthly reports, so this report gives highlights about the
Ursa Labs team&#39;s work from August up until now. With 2019 nearly behind us,
this also gives us a moment to reflect on everything that&#39;s been accomplished
this year and look forward to next year. We hope to write a blog post soon
discussing the big picture plan ahead for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Columnar File Performance Check-in for Python and R: Parquet, Feather, and FST</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-10-columnar-perf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-10-columnar-perf/</guid>
      <description>Since the founding of Ursa Labs in 2018, one of our focus areas has been accelerating data access to binary file formats for Python and R programmers. My first semi-formal collaboration with the R community was the creation of the Feather file format with Hadley Wickham shortly after the Apache Arrow project was started. Since then I have focused my energy on the Arrow project to build high performance data processing infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ursa Labs June and July 2019 Report</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-06-07-monthly-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-06-07-monthly-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like April and May, I&#39;m continuing to give bimonthly rather than monthly
reports. As usual it was a busy couple of months. See the end of the report for
the team&#39;s full changelog of patches contributed to Apache Arrow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ursa Labs April-May 2019 Report</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-04-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 20:26:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-04-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our last report was for March 2019, so I have rolled up two months
into one. There have been a number of exciting developments in the
project in the last couple of months. See the end of the report for
the team&#39;s full changelog of patches contributed to Apache Arrow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ursa Labs March 2019 Report</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 20:26:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first quarter of 2019 has now wrapped up. In March we spent a good amount
of time focused on getting the 0.13.0 Apache Arrow release out of the door. I
will mention a few development highlights from the month and provide the full
changelog of patches later in the post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ursa Labs February 2019 Report</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 20:26:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The team had a busy 28 days this February. The Apache Arrow community is
discussing a 0.13 release toward the end of March, so we spent February helping
the project toward the next release milestone. We have been pushing projects on
multiple fronts and discuss some of those here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ursa Labs January 2019 Report</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 20:26:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/2019-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had a busy January that went by too quickly. After a high-intensity 3 months
of development, we helped release &lt;a href=&#34;http://arrow.apache.org/release/0.12.0.html&#34;&gt;Apache Arrow 0.12&lt;/a&gt; on January 20th. A
good chunk of our time was spent fighting fires (in packaging and builds)
related to the continued expansion of the project in recent months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Ursa Labs&#39;s partnership with NVIDIA</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/ursa-labs-partner-nvidia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 20:26:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/ursa-labs-partner-nvidia/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m excited to announce that NVIDIA AI Labs has signed on as a supporter of Ursa Labs. NVIDIA&#39;s new open source RAPIDS data science platform uses Apache Arrow for an interoperable representation of tabular data (data frames). We are looking forward to collaborating on our respective development roadmaps and growing the ecosystem of projects that use Arrow.
This new financial support will enable us to grow our team of full-time open source software developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Ursa Labs: an innovation lab for open source data science</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/blog/announcing-ursalabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 20:26:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/blog/announcing-ursalabs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Funding open source software development is a complicated subject. I’m excited
to announce that I’ve founded &lt;a href=&#34;https://ursalabs.org&#34;&gt;Ursa Labs&lt;/a&gt;, an
independent development lab with the mission of innovation in data science
tooling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Ursa Labs</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Founded in 2018, Ursa Labs is an industry-funded development group specializing in open source data science tools. It is dedicated to advancing the state of the art in high-productivity, high-performance, cross-language software for data scientists. Ursa Labs is now a part of Ursa Computing.
Our Mission We founded Ursa Labs with the goal of helping make Apache Arrow a robust and reliable next-generation computational foundation for in-memory analytics and data science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Ursa Labs</title>
      <link>https://ursalabs.org/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ursalabs.org/support/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for your interest in Ursa Labs. We depend on external financial support to provide a livelihood for software engineers creating open source software for the public good.
We are looking to build relationships with organizations which can provide either:
 Direct financial support, which will be used to provide salary and benefits for software engineers working in the lab Engineering collaborations on our roadmap  To contact us about ways to support Ursa Labs, please email us at info@ursalabs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>